不正視聴!?
なんだ？
いったい何が起きている？
What is that?
What is going on?!
(カツユ)ナルト君が 今まさに➡
Naruto is fighting Pain right now!
ペインと戦っています！
ナルトが!?
Naruto?!
(チョウジ)戦ってるって!?
たった１人で？
Fighting?! By himself?
はい 手を出さないように
とのことです。
Yes. We are told not to interfere.
(キバ)ナルトを信じるしかねえだろ。
Then all we can do is
have faith in Naruto.
こうなったらよ。
ワン！
《ヒナタ : ナルト君が…》
Naruto...
間違いありません。
ナルト君ですよ 確かに！
There's no mistake!
It's definitely Naruto!
ナルト君が たった１人で…。
He's fighting alone!
No, Lady Hinata!
ダメです ヒナタ様！
But Naruto is risking his life
for our village!
でも ナルト君は里のために！
あんな戦いに入っても
ナルト君の足手まといになるだけ！
If you enter such a battle,
you will only get in his way
ナルト君を困らせるだけです！
and put him at risk!
《ナルト君…》
Naruto...
Nine-Tails, Captured!
(ナルト)チクショウ オヤビンたちまで！
Damn it... He even took out
Chief Toad and the others!
(フカサク)おい さっさと
幻術をやるじゃわい！
Hey! We must hurry and
launch the genjutsu.
(シマ)みんなの目の前で
デュエットなんて こっぱずかしい！
Performing a duet before everyone
is so embarrassing.
つべこべ言わずに やるんじゃ！
わかっとるがね！
Quit complaining and do it!
I know already!
この幻術は
仙術チャクラを多量に使用する。
This genjutsu requires an enormous
amount of Sage Jutsu Chakra.
つまり 術を発動するまで
少し時間がかかるんじゃ。
In other words,
it will take a little time before
the jutsu activates.
俺は インターバルの５秒間を狙う。
I'm gonna go for that
five-second interval!
As soon as you take in
enough Sage Jutsu Chakra,
仙術チャクラが練れたら
幻術を始めてくれ！
start the genjutsu!
ただし ナルトちゃんも
仙術チャクラを練ってくれとる➡
Remember... You only have
one Shadow Clone left
to take in Sage Jutsu Chakra
for you, Naruto-boy.
影分身は あと１人。
それがなくなったら
言ったとおり➡
Once that's gone,
it'll be impossible to fight
戦闘中には動くなの
仙術チャクラは練れん。
while taking in Sage Jutsu Chakra,
as it requires you not to move.
And your Sage Mode will
run out in five minutes.
もう 仙人モードは
５分も もたんのじゃし。
動くなの 仙術チャクラを練る役目を
作っとくのは よう考えたがの。
Using Shadow Clones to
help you maintain stillness
and take in Sage Jutsu Chakra
was a good idea.
なんで もっと人数を
増やしとかんかったんじゃ？
But why didn't you make
more of them?
右を見るときに
左も見るようなもんじゃ。
It's like trying to look to the right
and to the left at the same time.
役割分担はしたが
仙術チャクラは練るのが難しいけん。
We've divided the task,
but taking in Sage Jutsu Chakra
is extremely difficult.
At Naruto-boy's current level,
two Shadow Clones was his limit.
今のナルトちゃんには
影分身は２人が限界じゃった。
その上 こっちの戦闘影分身も
３人分しかできねえ。
On top of that, I can only produce
three Shadow Clones for battle.
あまり こっちで
大人数にしちまうと➡
Any more would interfere with
those taking in Sage Jutsu Chakra.
仙術チャクラ練ってる側が乱れちまう。
そうか どっちにしろ
あまり長引くのは やばいの。
I see... Either way, prolonging things
isn't to our advantage.
お前は確かに強い。
You are strong indeed.
ペインが ここまで
やられたのは初めてだ。
This is the farthest Pain
has ever been pushed.
だが 万象天引。
However...
Universal Pull.
ここまでにしておこう。
That's enough.
《すまん ナルトちゃん！
持ちこたえてくれ！》
Forgive us, Naruto-boy!
Just hang in there!
ナルト君！
Naruto...
安心しろ 殺しはしない。
大事な人柱力だからな。
Don't worry. I won't kill you.
You are a precious Jinchuriki.
ヘッ こんなの大して
痛かねえってばよ！
Hah, it doesn't hurt at all!
仙人モード なめんなよ！
今度は こっちから…。
Don't underestimate
my Sage Mode!
Now it's my turn to...
確かに それは厄介だ。
You are right. That is a problem.
《なんだ？ 力が抜けていく
What's happening?
I'm losing power...
そうか コイツ…。
I get it! This guy is sucking out
my Sage Jutsu Chakra!
俺から仙術チャクラを
吸収しやがったのか》
九尾 捕獲完了。
Capture of the Nine-Tails,
accomplished.
《幻術の発動まで もう少し。
Just a bit longer and
we'll be able to use genjutsu.
耐えてくれ ナルトちゃんよ》
Hang in there, Naruto-boy!
まだ… まだだ。
You don't have me...yet.
なかなかしぶといな。
Quite tenacious, aren't you?
So that's how it is.
《なるほど そういうことか。
なら 動けねえから
ちょうどいい》
Well, it's just perfect since
I can't move.
やっと 観念したか。
So you've finally resigned yourself.
うん？
自然エネルギーは➡
You know, Nature Energy is
really hard to control.
扱いが難しいんだってばよ。
これは…。
《そうか あのペイン。
What is this?
I see... That Pain underwent
a petrified frog transformation
ナルトちゃんから 仙術チャクラを
取り込みすぎて➡
from absorbing too much
of Naruto-boy's Sage Jutsu Chakra!
蛙石化してしもうたんか》
うお～!!
仙術チャクラ
それなりに リスクがあったようだな。
Sage Jutsu Chakra has its risks,
after all.
これで お前１人だけだ。
Now, it's just you...
それは 少し違うな。
Well...not quite.
どういうことだってばよ？
What do you mean?
(カツユ)
このペインたちは 操り人形です。
These Pains are puppets.
陰で ペインたちを操っている輩。
本体がいるようです。
There is another manipulating
these Pains.
The real Pain.
The real Pain?!
本体？
よし準備できた いくで母ちゃん！
あいよ！
All right, we're ready.
Let's do it, Ma!
Gotcha!
うわあ～！
父ちゃん！
じいちゃん仙人！
Pa!
Geezer Sage!
《あの幻術は もう懲りてるよ》
I've had enough of
that genjutsu.
(いの)シカマル！
Shikamaru!
いの 無事だったのか。
うん。
Ino! You're alive!
Yes...
でも シズネさんが。
But...Lady Shizune...
おい それって…。
What?! You mean...
わりゃ クソ！
Aw dammit!
イテテ。
Oww...!
体じゅうの骨が いってもうた。
Every bone in my body is broken!
I see... Is that what happened?
(シカマル)そうか そんなことが。
私たちが
もっとしっかりしてたら。
If we had been more diligent,
this would never have...
こんなことには…。
(シカマル)
シズネ先輩の死をムダにはできねえ。
We can't let Lady Shizune's death
be in vain.
先輩が解こうした
ペインの謎を解き明かして➡
We'll unravel the mystery
she tried to solve,
その本体ってのを見つけ出すまで
泣き言はなしだ。
and find the real Pain.
You can whine
after all this is over!
(シカク)
シカマル もう少し やんわりとだな。
Shikamaru...
Can't you say it to her nicer?
No, he is right, Shikaku.
(いのいち)
いや シカマルの言うとおりだシカク。
我々のできることは➡
The way to make ourselves useful
すぐにでも ペイン本体の居場所を
探し出すことだ。
is to find the location of the real Pain
as soon as possible.
いのいち お前ほどの術者なら➡
Inoichi, you're a skillful jutsu user.
Are you able to pick up
the enemy's chakra
敵のチャクラを拾って
逆探知できないのか。
and trace his whereabouts?
すでにやってみた。
I already tried.
But the enemy is constantly
changing their chakra frequency.
だが 敵は 常に
チャクラの周波を変えていやがる。
逆探知は無理だ。
A trace back is impossible.
(いのいち)
ペインは かなりのやり手だよ。
Pain is quite adept.
Pa!
父ちゃん！
テメエ！
Bastard!
万象天引。
Universal Pull.
ぐわぁ～!!
これで 少しは
おとなしくなるか？ 九尾。
Has this tamed you a little,
Nine-Tails?
テメエは 何だ？
いったい何だってんだ。
What are you?!
Just what do you want?!
なんで こんなことしやがる？
Why are you doing all of this?!
なんで か…。
Why, you ask?
出来事は いつも突然だ。
Things always happen
without warning.
理由は後になって気づく。
And the reason becomes
apparent afterwards.
この状況 そうだな
少し話をしよう。
This situation...
Perhaps I will explain to you.
ペインと接触した人たちから
カツユを通して➡
Use Katsuyu as a medium and
gather every piece of data available
なるべく詳しく
情報を集めるんだ。
from those who have
encountered Pain.
死んだ者も何かしらの情報を
残してるかもしれねえ。
The dead may have left
some information as well.
死体を運び出してでも
徹底的にやるぞ。
Even if we have to haul dead bodies,
find out all we can!
死体を運ぶ？
Haul dead bodies...
待てよ そうか わかってきたぞ
ペイン本体の居場所が。
Wait... I think I know where
to find the real Pain!
どういうこと？
何か気づいたんすか？
What do you mean?
Did you figure something out?
ああ 自来也様が捕らえた➡
Yeah...
Back when I looked into
the mind of the Hidden Rain ninja
あの雨隠れの忍の頭の中を
覗いたときのことだ。
who was captured by Lord Jiraiya...
その男は 仲間と
死体を運ぶ仕事をしていた。
His duty was to deliver bodies
with his partner.
((長年の勘でわかる。
It's a knack I got from
years of experience.
こりゃ 女だ。
This one's a woman.
俺たちが いつも死体を運ぶ➡
The highest tower in the village
where we always deliver these bodies...
(この里でいちばん高い塔))
死体を運ぶ？
そう。
Deliver bodies?
Yes... Your earlier remark
triggered my memory.
お前のさっきの言葉で ピンときた。
(いのいち)いいか まず１つに
チャクラ信号を送信する側は➡
Now listen...
First of all, it's basic knowledge that
one who transmits chakra signals
なるべく 受信体の
近くにいることが常識だ。
must be as close to
the receiver as possible.
でだ その男は
雨隠れにある数ある塔の中で➡
And...
Of the several towers that exist
in Hidden Rain Village,
いちばん高い塔に
死体を運んでいた。
this man was delivering bodies
to the tallest tower.
そして 雨隠れでは ペインは
そのいちばん高い塔にいると➡
It was rumored in
Hidden Rain Village
that Pain could be found
in the tallest tower.
噂されていたようだ。
((実はな あそこに ペイン様が
いらっしゃるんじゃないかと➡
Actually... Rumor has it
that Lord Pain lives up there.
(噂されている))
(いのいち)
そして ペインとして現れた女。
And the woman who appeared as Pain...
あれは その高い塔に運び込まれた
女の死体と同じだった。
She was the same body
as the woman
who was delivered to
the tallest tower.
その塔は チャクラ受信機である
黒い棒を➡
So this tower was the laboratory where
those black rod-like Chakra Receivers
死体に埋め込んでペインを作る➡
were implanted into corpses
to create the Pains.
実験場にも
なっていたってことだ。
…で それが どうして➡
And how is that connected to
the real Pain's whereabouts?
ペイン本体の居場所と
つがなるんすか？
チャクラ信号を送信するために
いちばん効率的な場所。
The best spot to send out
chakra signals...
より広く遠くへ
送信するためには➡
It had to be the tallest tower
with the widest and farthest reach.
いちばん高い塔じゃなきゃ
いけなかったんだ。
なるほど
ということは つまり➡
I see... That means...
ペイン本体は 木ノ葉近くの➡
the real Pain is in the highest spot
close to Leaf Village.
いちばん高い場所にいる
ってことになる。
よし なら 高い場所を
しらみつぶしに捜索するぞ。
All right! So we'll search
every single spot
that is at a high altitude!
You asked me why I am
doing all of this.
お前は なんで
こんなことをする？ と➡
俺に問うたが➡
Even if I told you why,
I doubt that would change anything.
その理由を
お前に話したところで➡
何も変わりはしないだろう。
But what if we tried to have
a discussion once more?
だが もう一度 ゆっくり
話をすれば どうだろうな？
お前と話すことなんてない！
I have nothing to discuss
with you.
俺の目的は 自来也先生も
成しえなかったことだ。
My goal is something even
Jiraiya Sensei was unable to achieve.
さっきも言ったがな➡
As I mentioned earlier...
平和を生み出し
正義を成すことだ。
Creating peace,
and bringing about justice.
平和 正義… ふざけんな！
Peace? Justice?
Yeah, right...
ふざけんな！
Don't give me that crap!
俺の師匠を！
My master! My sensei!
俺の先生を！
俺の仲間を！
My friends! My village!
俺の里を！
こんなにしやがった
お前なんかが➡
After everything you've done,
えらそうに
ほざいてんじゃねえ！
don't you dare talk about
peace and justice!
なら お前の目的はなんだ？
Then tell me what your goal is?
お前を ぶっ倒して➡
I'm gonna kill you!
And bring peace back
to the Ninja World!
俺が この忍の世界を
平和にしてやる！
そうか… それは 立派なことだ。
I see... That is noble of you.
それこそ正義だな。
That is justice indeed. However...
だが 俺の家族を➡
My family...
俺の仲間を 俺の里を➡
My friends...
My village...
この里と同じようにした
お前たち 木ノ葉の忍だけが➡
They suffered the same fate
as this village,
by you Hidden Leaf Ninjas.
平和と正義を口にすることを
許されるわけではないだろう。
How is it fair to only allow you people
to preach about peace and justice?
どういうことだってばよ？
What are you talking about?!
火の国… そして 木ノ葉は
大きくなりすぎた。
The Land of Fire and the Hidden Leaf
had grown too big.
国益を守るため
大国同士の戦争で➡
To protect its national interests,
it forced feudal clans to wage war
against each other,
自国の利益を
獲得する必要があった。
and profited from it.
でなければ 国 里の民が飢える。
Otherwise, the nation and the people
of the villages would have starved.
だが その大国の戦場になるのは➡
However, our little nation and
its villages became the battlefields
俺たちの小さな国と里だった。
for the Great Nation's war.
そのたびに 我々の国は
荒らされ 疲弊していった。
And each time, our nation was ravaged
and laid to waste.
幾たびかの戦争を経て
大国は安定した。
After all the fighting subsided,
things stabilized in the Great Nation.
我ら小国に多くの痛みを残してな。
And our little nation was left
to suffer the pain and misery.
お前も俺も 目指すものは同じだ。
You and I seek the same thing.
自来也先生の言っていた
平和を成そうとしている。
We are trying to establish the peace
that Jiraiya Sensei so desired.
お前も俺も 何も変わらない。
You and I are not different at all.
互いの正義のために動く。
We each act according to
our own sense of justice.
俺が
木ノ葉に対してやった正義は➡
The justice I delivered
to the Leaf Village
お前が 俺に
やろうとしていることと同じだ。
is no different from what
you are trying to do to me.
大切なものを失う痛みは
誰も同じ。
The pain of losing something dear
to you is the same.
お前も俺も
その痛みを知る者同士だ。
And both of us know
that pain all too well.
お前は お前の正義のために。
You have your justice...
俺は 俺の正義のために。
And I have mine.
俺たちは 正義という名の
復讐へと➡
We are both ordinary men,
駆り立てられた 普通の人間だ。
driven to seek vengeance
under the banner of justice.
だが 復讐を正義というならば➡
However, if there is justice
in vengeance,
その正義は 更なる 復讐を生み➡
then justice will only breed
more vengeance.
憎しみの連鎖が始まる。
And trigger a cycle of hatred.
今 その事象の中に生き
過去を知り 未来を予感する。
We are living in the middle of
such a phenomenon right now.
We know what the past
has been and
we can predict what
the future will be.
それが 歴史だと知る。
That is history as we know it.
人は 決して 理解し合うことの
できない生き物だと➡
So we cannot help
but believe that
human beings are incapable
of understanding each other.
悟らざるを得ない。
忍の世界は
憎しみに支配されている。
The world of the ninja
is ruled by hatred.
However...
((自来也 : だがのう…。
こんなわしでも この忍の世に➡
even I can see there's too much
hate in our Ninja World.
憎しみが はびこっているのは
わかる。
憎しみ…。
Hate?
その憎しみを どうにかしたい
とは思っとるんだが➡
And I've wanted to do
something about this hatred,
どうしたらいいのか
わしにも まだわからん。
yet I'm not sure what must be done.
だが いつかは➡
But I have faith that
there will come a time
人が 本当の意味で
理解し合える時代が来ると➡
when people can truly understand
one another.
わしは信じとる。
なんか 難しいってばよ。
It all sounds kinda complicated.
答えが見つからんかったときは➡
And if I can't find the answer,
perhaps I will entrust you to find it.
その答えを
お前に託すとしようかのう。
おっす！ エロ仙人の頼みなら➡
Yes, sir! I can't turn you down,
can I, Pervy Sage?
(しかたねえってばよ！))
お前なら 平和を作るため➡
How would you confront this hatred,
in order to create peace?
この憎しみと どう向き合う？
お前の答えを聞こう。
I want to hear your answer.
わかんねえ そんなこと。
I don't have an answer...
to something like that.
俺は その憎しみの連鎖を
止めるために➡
I formed the Akatsuki in order
to stop this cycle of hatred.
暁を立ち上げた。
俺なら止めることができる。
I can put an end to it.
そのためには
九尾の その力が必要なのだ。
For that...I need the power
of your Nine-Tails.
すべての尾獣の力を使い➡
I will use the power of
every Tailed Beast
この里を潰した数十倍の力をもつ
尾獣兵器を作る。
to create a Tailed Beast Weapon,
many times more potent than
the power that destroyed this village.
一国を一瞬で潰せるほどのな。
A power enough to wipe out
an entire nation instantly.
尾獣兵器？
A Tailed Beast Weapon?!
本当の痛みを世界へ知らしめ➡
The world will know real pain.
その痛みの恐怖で戦いを抑止し➡
The fear instilled by that pain
would prevent wars.
世界を安定と平和へ導くのだ。
And the world will be on
the road to stability and peace.
だからって そんな平和…。
But that kind of peace...
そんなの嘘っぱちじゃねえかよ。
It's nothing but a fake!
人間は そんなに
賢い生き物ではない。
Humans are not the most intelligent
of creatures.
そうでもしなければ➡
This is the only way that
peace can be achieved.
平和を作れないのだ。
やがて その痛みも➡
And after several decades,
何十年と時が経てば 癒えていく。
that pain too will
eventually fade with time.
抑止力は低下し➡
It will no longer be a deterrent
そして また人々は争い➡
and humanity will begin to
battle once more.
今度は
自分たちで尾獣兵器を使い➡
This time, they themselves will
use the Tailed Beast Weapon
本当の痛みを再確認する。
against one another and
reconfirm what true pain is.
(長門)そして また
一時の平和が訪れる。
この終わりなき
憎しみの連鎖の流れのなかに➡
痛みにより
一時の平和を生み出すこと。
それが俺の願いだ。
ゴホッ ゴホッ…。
(小南)長門
あまり無理をしないで。
もうずいぶんチャクラを使ってる。
平和は目の前だ。
(サクラ)ヒナタ！
サクラさん。
新しいエンディング あれ 何なのよ？
えっ どういうことですか？
ヒロインの私を差し置いて➡
なんで１人で
エンディングに出られるわけ？
そ そんな 私 知りません…。
これよ これ！
まさかアンタ スタッフに賄賂でも
贈ったんじゃないでしょうね？
そ そんなことしてません。
しかも自転車なんて…
忍者なら走りなさいよね。
サクラちゃん あきらめろってばよ。
ナルト…。
「NARUTO」のスタッフには
ヒナタファンがいてさ➡
今回は そのスタッフが
暴走して作ったって話だぜ。
何よ それ！
それに ちゃんと
曲も聴いてほしいってばよ。
こんだけ
自転車連呼されちまったら➡
どんな優秀なスタッフでも
自転車に乗せざるを得ねえだろ。
ほう なるほど！
って そうじゃなくて！
こら～っ スタッフ！
私のエンディングを作りなさいよ！
私のエンディングを！
しゃんなろ～！
ああ…。
あ…。
(ナツ)どけ ミッシェル！
それ以上
姉さんに近づかないで。
私たちを放っておいて。
そうすれば 命までは奪わない。
んだと！